

Alexander Ротароv

Moscow, Russia | +7 (985) 389-24-21 alexander.potapov.w@yandex.ru

in linkedin | 🖸 github

SUMMARY

Frontend (TypeScript, React) 3D Graphics (C++, Vulkan) developer. Currenty working in a startup as a Frontend developer on a next-gen web spreadsheets app (Excel/GSheets competitor). Our stack incluse TypeScript, React, C++ (WASM). Previously worked in a gamedev company as a 3D graphics developer (C++, DirectX11, Vulkan), developing new version of company's internal game engine in Vulkan. Interested in both low-level programming optimizations and in developing high-level, used-facing features.

EDUCATION _

HIGHER SCHOOL OF ECONOMICS UNIVERSITY

2020 - Now / Moscow, Russia

B.S IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

• Calculus, Linear Algebra, Discrete Mathematics, Software Development, Operating Systems, Computer Architecture

EXPERIENCE

NANOSEMANTICS

October 2020 - June 2021 / Moscow, Russia

C++/PYTHON SOFTWARE ENGINEER

• Written a compiler for internal company programming language (AI dialoge patterns)

EAGLE DYNAMICS

August 2021 - May 2022 / Moscow, Russia

3D GRAPHICS DEVELOPER

• Ported EDGE game engine to Vulkan. Created utilities for cross-compiling FX shaders to SPIR-V

BRICKS

May 2022 - Now / Remote

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

• Implementation of core features of Excel-like spreadsheet (rendering, charts, tables). TypeScript + Solid.JS/React.JS. Canvas DOM rendering

SKILLS __

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES Experienced: C++ | TypeScript Familiar: C# | Python

GRAPHICS PROGRAMMING Deferred Rendering | Physically-Based Rendering | Render Graph | Vulkan API | OpenGL

FRONTEND TypeScript | ReactJS | WebAssembly Languages Native: Russian Fluent: English

OPEN-SOURCE PROJECTS _____

MxEngine	General-purpose 3D game engine (deferred rendering, PBR, physics, audio, editor tools)	github
VAL	Render Graph-based Vulkan rendering library (automatic barriers, shader reflection)	github
FLUID SIMULATION	2D realtime fluid simulation from GPUGems book (with CUDA as compute backed)	github
PATH TRACER	GLSL path tracer (based on MxEngine, supports diffuse, reflective and transparent objects)	github
ANGOURIMATH	Symbolic algebra library for C# (one of main contributors, worked on analytic solvers)	Laithub